Amlan Banaji

PhD student in Mathematics at St Andrews

Curriculum Vitae

Website: amlan-banaji.github.io

Nationality: UK

Email: afb8 "at" st-andrews.ac.uk

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am primarily interested in the geometry and dimension theory of fractal sets and measures. I have worked extensively with fractals generated by conformal and non-conformal iterated function systems. Much of my research has focused on interpolating between different notions of dimension. I am interested in finding connections between fractal geometry and other areas of mathematics.

PUBLICATIONS AND PREPRINTS

- Intermediate dimensions of infinitely generated attractors (with J. M. Fraser), 29pp To appear in **Transactions of the American Mathematical Society**. *arXiv*
- Attainable forms of intermediate dimensions (with A. Rutar), 26pp To appear in **Annales Fennici Mathematici**. <u>arXiv</u>
- Intermediate dimensions of Bedford-McMullen carpets with applications to Lipschitz equivalence (with I. Kolossváry), 47pp Submitted. arXiv
- Generalised intermediate dimensions, 43pp Submitted. arXiv

EDUCATION

University of St Andrews

2019-present

PhD Mathematics (in progress)

Topic: Fractal geometry and dimension theory

With the Analysis Research Group

Supervisors: Prof. Jonathan Fraser (primary), Prof. Kenneth Falconer

Full scholarship from the Leverhulme Trust

University of St Andrews

2018-2019

MSc Mathematics, Distinction

GPA: 19.5/20. Ranked 1st in the Faculty of Science and Medicine

Dissertation:

Solvability of Partial Differential Equations on Fractal Domains (Score: 19.1/20, supervised by Professor Kenneth Falconer)

University of Cambridge,

King's College 2015-2018

BA (Hons) Mathematics

Selected Part II courses: Linear Analysis, Analysis of Functions, Topics in Analysis, Differential Geometry, Riemann Surfaces, Logic and Set Theory

Thomas Tallis Sixth Form

2013-2015

A-Levels:

 $Mathematics(A^*)$, $Further Mathematics(A^*)$, $Physics(A^*)$, $Chemistry(A^*)$, *History(A), Extended Project Qualification(A*, AS level)*

PRIZE

2019: **Postgraduate Gray Prize** for the best taught postgraduate student in the Faculty of Science and Medicine at the University of St Andrews.

TALKS

I have given 14 talks (listed at amlan-banaji.github.io/talks) at conferences and seminar series including:

- <u>Junior Ergodic Theory Meeting</u> (ICMS, Edinburgh (March 2022) and online (March 2021))
- Workshop on affine and overlapping iterated function systems (Bristol, 11/5/22)
- Dynamics and Group Geometry Early Researchers Seminar (DAGGER) (Warwick, May 2022 and March 2021)
- Analysis Seminar (St Andrews, May 2022, October 2021 and June 2020)

EXPERIENCE

Teaching undergraduate tutorials at the University of St Andrews:

2019 – 2021: MT2502 Analysis (8 groups total)

2021: MT2505 Abstract Algebra (2 groups)

2020: MT1003 Pure and Applied Mathematics (2 groups)

- *2018 onwards*: **Tutoring** mathematics (undergraduate, A level and STEP) with Oxford Exclusif Tutorial Agency, PhD Tutors, Sishu Chinese School, and privately.
- 2018: LMS-funded **Cambridge Summer Research in Mathematics (SRIM) project** on Leray-Schauder Topological Degree Theory and its applications to Partial Differential Equations.
- 2017: internship at market research company Kantar TNS, working as a **data scientist** for the social media team, using Python.

SERVICE

- 2022: Proceedings of the Royal Society of Edinburgh, Section A: Mathematics. Referee.
- 2022: Journal of Mathematical Analysis and Applications. **Referee.**
- 2021: Postgraduate Interdisciplinary Mathematics Symposium (PIMS), St Andrews. Co-organiser.
- 2019–2021: St Andrews Mindfulness Society. **Treasurer.**

MEMBERSHIP OF PROFESSIONAL BODIES

- 2019–present: Associate Member of the <u>Institute of Mathematics and its Applications</u> (AMIMA)
- 2020–present: Edinburgh Mathematical Society

INTERESTS AND SKILLS

- Languages: English (native), German (conversational, A* at GCSE), Hindi (conversational)
- Music: Piano (grade 8), Clarinet (toured Canada and Venice)
- **Sport:** running, badminton, chess